caymanchem.com 2015-12-03

# Privacy Statement || Cayman Chemical | Supplier

## Introduction

This privacy statement covers the sites 

  * caymanchem.com
  * caymanchemical.com
  * caymanchemicals.com
  * caymenchem.com
  * caymaneurope.com
  * caymanpharma.com
  * caymanpharma.cz

operated by Cayman Chemical Company, hereafter referred to as "Cayman sites." Because Cayman wants to demonstrate its commitment to user privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices. This policy details: 

  1. What personally identifiable information Cayman collects.
  2. What organizations collect the information. 
  3. How Cayman uses the information.
  4. With whom Cayman may share user information. 
  5. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  6. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Cayman control. 
  7. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

The key points of this policy are: 

  * Cayman collects fine-grained information about the use of our web sites. 
  * Cayman doesn't share personally identifiable information outside the company. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should contact Cayman staff: [Website Feedback](https://www.caymanchem.com/app/template/Contact.vm;jsessionid=A717CD8E5F19AF36C3320A2B73EE13C3). 

Cayman Chemical Company complies with the U.S.- EU Safe Harbor Framework and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Cayman Chemical Company has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Cayman Chemical Company’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. Cayman Chemical Company also has a separate policy that applies to certain personal data that Cayman receives in the United States from the European Union and Switzerland, called the Cayman Chemical Safe Harbor Privacy Statement which can be reached [here](https://www.caymanchem.com/app/template/PrivacySafeHarbor.vm;jsessionid=A717CD8E5F19AF36C3320A2B73EE13C3). 

## Information Collection and Use

### Information Collection

Cayman Chemical Company is the sole owner of the information collected on the Cayman sites. Cayman Chemical Company collects information from our users at several different points on the Cayman sites. 

#### Website Analytics

Information specific to the use of the Cayman sites, including which pages are visited, what technology is used (operating system, browser, etc.), and user demographic data, is collected through Google Analytics, which uses cookies to identify and track website visits. Customer demographics, including age, gender, and interests, are collected with Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Any information gathered with regard to the use of our website (either by registered Cayman sites users or by anonymous users) is used solely to improve Cayman sites and to better serve our customers and online visitors. 

#### Registration

In order to use some features this site, a user must first register with us via phone or web. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he or she has expressed interest. 

#### Order

We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customers' orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. 

#### Contact Forms

Our site includes several forms used to contact various Cayman staff departments. Information supplied on these forms is used only in relation to the specific issue you contact us about. It is not stored. 

#### Server Logs

Like most sites, we keep logs of our web server's operations. These logs include numerous data about each web request: 

  * date and time
  * IP address of requestor
  * Cayman site login name, if available
  * page or action requested
  * success or failure code
  * location of page containing link user clicked, if applicable
  * user screen resolution, when available
  * other information as configured by web administrator

#### Other Information

We log users' screen resolutions, when it is possible to do so. We use this information solely to guide web design choices. 

### Information Use

#### Storage

Cayman stores collected information indefinitely. 

#### Web Usage Reports

Web usage data is used to generate a variety of periodic and _ad hoc_ reports, many of which include personally identifiable information. 

#### New Product Update Email

If a user wishes to subscribe to our new product update email, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. 

#### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service-related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

### Sharing

#### Courts

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our web site. 

#### Third Party Intermediaries

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

### Distributors and Subsidiaries

We may share aggregate information with our distributors and subsidiaries. We do not share personally identifiable information with them. 

### Business Transitions

In the event Cayman Chemical Company goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

### Others

Apart from these exceptions, we share personal information with no one. 

## Links

This site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Cayman Chemical Company, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this site. 

## Frames

Select other sites may frame content from this site, meaning that information from the Cayman sites appears with branding, navigation, and utility features of another site. In these cases, this privacy statement applies to the framed content, but not to the other matter. Users are encouraged to review the privacy policies of these other sites, for they may differ from the policy of the Cayman sites. 

## Security

This site takes reasonable precautions to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

### Online

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when users are just 'surfing'. 

This sensitive information moves between the web server and Cayman's corporate network via a Virtual Private Network tunnel. This means a high level of security, comparable to that protecting data between the user's computer and the Cayman web server. 

Cayman's internal network is protected by reasonable security systems and practices. 

### Off-line

While we use SSL and VPN technology to protect sensitive information online, we also take precautions to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is stored in facilities with restricted access. 

If users have any questions about the security at our site, users can contact Cayman staff: [Website Feedback](https://www.caymanchem.com/app/template/Contact.vm;jsessionid=A717CD8E5F19AF36C3320A2B73EE13C3)

## Correcting, Updating, Deleting, or Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can be done by contacting [customer service](https://www.caymanchem.com/app/template/account%2CHome.vm;jsessionid=A717CD8E5F19AF36C3320A2B73EE13C3). 

If users would like to opt out of Google Analytics tracking, they can do so with the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

## Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

## Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us: [Website Feedback](https://www.caymanchem.com/app/template/Contact.vm;jsessionid=A717CD8E5F19AF36C3320A2B73EE13C3).
